他只是去拿吃的 你这个疯女人
He was reaching for the food, you mad cunt!
埃提斯是我们一边的
Attius stands with us.
他替该死的罗马人说话
He stands a fucking Roman.
克拉苏不让我刮脸
Crassus denies me sharpened blade.
为什么
Under what purpose?
他的想法
Personal matter.
西利西亚的强盗
Brigands of Cilicia.
海盗
Pirates?
市政官跟我有个协议
The Aedile and I had an arrangement.
我不愿意求饶
I will not beg for my life.
找到印章
Do this thing…
你们就自由了
And you will be released.
决斗的那人…跑了
Your man make fight gone.
乌尔比安
Ulpianus?
告诉我他们在哪儿
Tell me where they are.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know who you speak of.
让你的人准备进攻
Tell your men to advance.
你父亲明确下令
Your father gave strict order not…
我父亲要的是能打仗的狼
My father desires a wolf of battle.
进攻
Advance!
都别动 都他妈的给老子坚守阵地
Stand ground, stand your fucking ground!
撤退
Retreat!
《斯巴达克斯：诅咒者之战》
《十一抽杀》
目前我们还有事情
There stands greater worry
比西利西亚人带进港的粮食更重要
than grain carried to port by Cilician shits.
没有粮食我们吃什么 拿空口承诺当饭吃吗
What would you have us feast upon? Promise of better days?
我希望吃罗马人的肉喝罗马人的血
I would see bellies filled with the death of Romans.
克拉苏肯定会派更多的军队来
Crassus is certain to dispatch more soldiers.
我们应该做好迎敌的准备
And we should be preparing to greet them.
我们正在准备
We are.
保证我们的人不要饿着肚子上战场
By ensuring our own do not go into battle weakened by hunger.
收帆 晚上在这儿过夜
Furl sails, we here for the night.
赫拉克里奥
Heracleo.
此行收获如何
How fares recent venture?
你要是口渴 那就天随人愿了
If you are of a thirst, the gods have shown favor.
你没带粮食来
You carry no grain?
我们从罗马人的船上抢来了一堆罐子
A clutch of amphoras so filled were liberated from Roman ship.
但是船长装的酒比粮食多
Yet its captain held more stock in drink than seed of bread.
我们不能拿酒充饥
Wine will not feed my people.
为防天寒 罗马人把大多收成
The Romans have stored most of their harvest
都放进粮仓了
against encroaching chill.
抢粮的难度自然就增加了
Difficulty rises in securing such bounty.
所以价钱也要涨
As does its price?
对
Yeah.
退后
Move back!
住手 不要冲动
Whoa, hold and fall to reason!
每人拿一把粮食 让他们离开码头
See each to a handful, and clear them from the docks.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus.
不少奴隶正徒步接近城门
More slaves taken afoot approach gate.
你给他们也一人分一把粮食吗
Will you see them to a handful as well?
你见过我妹妹吗
Do you know of my sister?
城池沦陷后我就再没见过她
I haven't laid eyes since the city fell.
不能把仅有的粮食浪费在
We should not be wasting what little food we have
- 该死的罗马人身上 - 你知道我意已决
- on fucking Romans. - You know my mind upon subject.
我跟克雷斯看法一样
I stand with Crixus towards it.
我答应莱塔的 就决不会反悔
I have given Laeta my word. It will not be broken.
求求你让我进去
Let me in, please!
进城前必须先交出武器
If you hold weapon you must give over before entering city!
我操
Fuck!
武器
Weapon?
就这个
Just this.
多谢
Merci.
我曾经也像他一样 好像是上辈子的事了
It seems a lifetime past, that I stood as him.
亮出烙印 看看你…
Show brand, and see what you…
亮出你的烙印
Show brand or mark,
证明你是奴隶 不是共和国的人
to prove you stand former slave and no friend of the Republic!
我们无处可去了
We have nowhere to go!
让我看看你的烙印
Show me your brand.
这是最厉害的武器了
The most fearsome weapons yet exposed.
再仔细点搜查我也没意见
I would take no offense to closer inspection…
打开包裹
Open bag!
放松点 兄弟
Put mind at ease, brother.
你在这里用不着钱
You'll have no need of this here.
斯巴达克斯不喜欢随身带钱的
Spartacus does not favor his people holding coin.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
她说她有克拉苏军队的消息
This one carries knowledge of Crassus' army.
离我们码头大概半天的路程
I say about a half day's march from our wharves.
多少人
How great a force?
据她说营地比城还大
Larger than fucking city by her word.
但他依然扎营不动
Yet he has made camp and holds advance.
如果真有那么多人 为什么要等
Why stay hand when it grips such numbers?
他早该提着老屌上来了 如果他认为…
He but grips his own fucking cock if he believes we will…
快跑
Run!
- 该死的罗马人 - 罗马人
- Fucking Romans! - The Romans!
关闭城门
Seal the gate!
快他妈让开
Give fucking way!
要求亮出烙印的时候 那些人就动手了
Fucking shits drew upon us when pressed to show brand.
多谢帮忙
Gratitude for assistance.
干掉你的敌人
There is no greater glory…
就是我最大的荣耀
than the death of your enemy.
朋友 让我看看你的烙印
I would lay eyes upon your brand friend.
这可有点麻烦
Well, that presents some difficulties.
要是没有 你麻烦更大
More so if you are absent one.
我主人把烙印都刺在私处旁边
My dominus branded all his slaves close to cock and cunt,
他喝醉时不分男女地通吃
equally enjoyed upon drunken nights.
我就用那把刀砍了他 割掉了烙印
With that knife I rid myself of him and his fucking mark…
衣服穿好 跟他们去吧
Fall to cover and join the others.
头砍下来 挂在城墙上
Sever their heads and set them to pike upon wall,
警告还有企图的人
as warning against future attempt.
克雷斯 甘尼克斯 艾力冈
Crixus, Gannicus, Agron…
我有重要的事跟你们说
I would have much needed words.
看你伤这么重 我心里不好受
It seizes heart, to know you in such pain.
看不见的地方伤得更重
A deeper wound stands removed from sight.
他还没来看你吗
He has not come to your side?
你把我送来营地时
I recall my father's grim visage
我依稀看见了父亲的严峻表情
when first you delivered me to encampment.
之后再也没见到他
I have not since laid eyes upon it.
别为这事担心
Place no worries in the absence.
统帅现在满脑子都是
The Imperator's mind is taken with thoughts
怎么剿灭斯巴达克斯
of coming battle against Spartacus.
我们要夺回那座城吗
We move to reclaim the city?
没有接到拔营的命令
I have received no order to break encampment.
不过派了一大队人马去北边
Though a large number of men have been dispatched north.
北边
North?
去干什么
Towards what purpose?
这种大事你父亲才不会告诉我
I do not hold your father's confidence in such matters.
也不会告诉我
We stand as one in such regard.
恺撒呢
What of Caesar?
他是不是揪住战败的事情不放
Does he circle fading corpse,
一心想代我父亲行使权力
eager to strip flesh of title as word and will of my father?
他不在这里
He no longer stands among us.
恺撒死了
Caesar has fallen?
他只是奉命办事去了
He but follows command.
下去吧
Leave us.
您给恺撒派了任务
You have given Caesar mission?
我盘算已久了
One always intended.
他秘密潜入了叛贼阵营
He secrets himself among the rebels,
加速他们的灭亡
to hasten their fall.
所以您不许他刮胡子
The reason you ordered he remain unshorn.
就是为了让他装扮成奴隶
To assume guise of errant slave.
伪装成狼 才能混进狼群
One must appear as wolf to be welcomed by the pack.
真是妙计
A plan well considered.
到时候我和您共同迎接胜利
I will stand by your side when it bears deadly fruit.
还没那么快
That day has not yet arrived.
好好养伤吧
Rest, allow wound to properly heal.
我代您行使权力 父亲
Uh, I am your word and your will, Father.
我的职责不是睡在这里
A position not commanded from upon back.
穿戴盔甲
See yourself to uniform.
我们去谈谈怎么惩罚你的部下
And let us break words towards your men's punishment,
让他们为冒进迎敌付出代价
for foolish attempt against Spartacus.
这就是克拉苏按兵不动的原因了
Mystery of Crassus holding advance falls to discovery.
操他妈的
The fucking cock on him.
他以为这几个人就能干掉我们
Believing a few men could end rebellion.
克拉苏作战的路数和别的罗马将领不同
Crassus does not move as the others we have faced.
他采用我们的战术
He adopts our strategies,
反过来对付我们
in effort to twist them against us.
我们应该多加小心
We should heed caution,
不要再打开城门
and see the gates remain closed.
我不能把冒着生命危险
I will not deny entry to those
逃离主人的奴隶拒之门外
who have risked life to break from their masters.
无论如何都为时已晚了
A thing born late in any regard.
已经有很多不知底细的人加入了我们
Many unknown to us have already passed through gate to join cause,
谁知道他们藏着什么坏心思
if outward form does not conceal darker intent.
如果真有这样的人
If there stand such among our ranks,
我们一定要查出来
we must see them exposed.
你们说了那么多如果
You scale a mountain of ifs.
我便来说一个大的
I would add to its peak.
如果混进来的奸贼把你给杀了
If you are struck down by one of your errant flock,
队伍没人带了怎么办
how would they fare absent guidance?
那就由克雷斯当首领
Crixus would see them upon proper path.
由你们几位群策群力 一同领导
With aid of wise council, gathered at this table.
诸神保佑
I pray to the gods
让这一天永不降临 兄弟
that is a day I never see come to pass, brother.
但如果真由我掌权了
Yet if I held sole command,
我一定迅速出击 打垮克拉苏
I would move swiftly against Crassus.
我也这么想
On this we share thought.
我们生来就渴望鲜血和战争
We are men of blood and battle.
但现在无所事事 众人焦躁不安
And the streets grow restless with idle purpose.
我们要按商量好的办
We must stay course agreed upon.
我们有城墙的保护
We hold advantage of city walls;
而克拉苏的军队无遮无挡
Crassus' legions will suffer on open plains,
同时我们可以训练更多的人
while we train swelling numbers
以逸待劳 痛击敌人
to see weakened foe to the afterlife.
要是那个埃提斯还活着
Would that Attius was still alive,
我们还能多造点武器
to forge more weapons.
你希望那个叛徒活着
You would see traitor live,
而脑浆迸裂的是妮维雅吗
and Naevia with brains upon fucking sand?
凡是解救罗马人的家伙
Let Attius stand as promised fate
都应该跟埃提斯一个下场
for all who would see Roman slaves from shackle.
先考虑眼前的事情
Fix mind upon the present,
看看新来的人有多少能耐
gauge prowess of those newly among us.
逃走的罗马人还没找到
Escaped Romans yet to be found,
克拉苏还在城门外
Crassus upon our gate,
你他妈的还要我去当教练
and you would have me play fucking doctore?
我是让你去看看有没有可疑的人
I would have you observe with watchful eye.
任何出乎意料的情况
Any that measure beyond expectation
都有可能让他们露出马脚
may reveal themselves more than they appear.
你们一起去办这事
Join brother, and see it done.
要是以前我肯定要说
A lifetime ago the words "Fucking Gauls"
「该死的高卢人」
would spring from mouth.
如果轮到克雷斯…
If it did fall to Crixus to…
你还没死呢
You are yet among the living,
我也不让你死
and I would see it remain so.
在那之前
Until threat is known,
我只当你的影子
I will be as fucking shadow.
那跟我走吧
Then darken heel,
去找个比我们更了解对手的人谈谈
and let us move to better know mind of our enemy.
我要是罗马人
If I stood Roman,
早就把你砍死了
my sword would have your life in favor of ass.
再来
Again!
那个人如果是卧底
If that man proves assassin,
我他妈就是天神了
then I am Jupiter's fucking cock.
没技术
No skill.
小鸡巴
Small cock.
你
You.
过来
Step forward.
我看到你拿刀杀那个罗马人了
I have witnessed your skill with knife upon the unsuspecting.
让我这行家试试你用剑的本事吧
Let us see how you fare with sword against more discerning eye.
真是浪费时间
We waste fucking effort.
如果真的混进了罗马人
If there is a Roman among them,
他们难道不会假装没学过用剑吗
would they not feign ignorance of the ways of fighting men?
野兽藏不住兽性
An animal cannot hide truer nature.
一旦无路可逃
When pressed to corner,
必定要露出尖牙和利爪
it will expose teeth and snap jaw.
你用剑倒是不生疏
You are no stranger to the clash of steel.
牧羊人可是有看家本领的
All shepherds are versed in sound.
很多人找机会抢别人家的畜生
Many seek to claim another master's stock upon hill and plain.
那你主人在下地狱之前
And what did your dominus call his defender of goat,
是怎么叫他家护羊使者的
before he slipped from grasp?
莱西克斯
Lyciscus.
他们给我起的
A name forced upon me.
我早想改名了
One I desire quickly shed.
改天我要再跟你比一次
I shall have rematch, upon a day.
你
You.
过来 尽量站住了别趴下啊
Step forward, and attempt to remain from fucking ground.
他们对你挺有兴趣
They take interest in you.
对你也有兴趣吧
Do they take it in you as well?
我看见你在城里
And with coin I saw you relieving those
搜刮那些难民的钱
seeking refuge within your walls?
再说一遍
Break such words again,
老子要了你的小命
and I shall relieve you of something far more valuable.
你误会我了 兄弟
Ah, you mistake intent, brother.
我只是想什么说什么
I mention deed only towards thoughts of my own.
对于有胆量抓住机遇的人来说
A city such as this holds great opportunity,
这座城可是大有所为啊
for those brave enough to seize it.
先不管训练的事情了
Let us place training aside for a moment.
探讨一下
Discuss the matter,
更有价值的东西
far more estimable.
她不愿住在宅子里
She turns from offer of villa
反倒要睡在稻草马粪旁边
for straw and the smell of shit?
不理解的人 她自然不想解释
For reason fallen upon understanding ear.
女人的心思
The mind of a woman.
真是猜不透
A foreign thing.
让我跟她单独谈谈 好问个明白
I would have words alone, and see it deciphered.
她没有威胁
She holds no threat.
我在门口等你
I shall place myself at entrance.
手里拿着剑
With sword clutched in fucking hand.
没想到屠影之英雄
Did not think the Slayer of the Shadow of Death
也需要保镖
had need of protector.
早上出了事 只好如此
Unfortunate precaution, in wake of morning's events.
听说了有人打进城内
Word carries of the attack.
有没有听说马科斯•克拉苏的消息呢
Does it also carry word of Marcus Crassus,
这次行动就是他安排的
the man who commanded it?
克拉苏
Crassus…
你很高兴嘛 知道罗马派这人来杀我
You are pleased with the man Rome has sent to kill me.
克拉苏办事的决绝无出其右
Crassus stands as no other in certainty of intent.
你不死 他不会罢休
He will not stop short of your end.
他不是第一个
He is not the first Roman
相信自己能办到这件事的罗马人了
to believe himself capable of the act.
在他之前的人没有哪个
Those that came before him did not hold wealth
拥有能让女神都嫉妒的财富
to turn Juno Moneta envious.
金钱在战场上没有多少价值
Coin holds little worth upon the field of battle.
那么聚敛财富的决心呢
What of a mind keen enough to amass it?
我们第一次见面时你谈到了与克拉苏的交易
Upon our first meeting you spoke of dealings with Crassus.
我要你把一切经过都告诉我
I would know of anything ear may have caught.
这种事既不能倒转乾坤
Such knowledge will not reverse sun,
也不能改变河流的走向
nor alter the course of river's fate.
那就没什么不能说的了
Then there stands no reason to deny request.
我们与克拉苏的交易
Our business with Crassus
仅限于粮食和货运 没有别的
concerned only grain and shipment, nothing more.
但我夫君讲了一件事
Yet my husband imparted story,
是那不勒斯的市政官告诉他的
shared by Aedile of Neapolis
提醒他不要重蹈覆辙
towards future dealings.
那人与克拉苏做了很多交易
The man was thick in negotiations with Crassus
他截到竞争对手所写的信件
when he intercepted message from reviled competitor,
发现对手给克拉苏的条件更好
offering more favorable terms to Crassus.
当看到利润
While seeing both profit
和重要客户就要消失
and valuable client soon to vanish,
市政官烧掉了那封信
the Aedile burned errant message,
并很快答应了克拉苏的要求
swiftly agreed to Crassus' demands.
几个月后他才发现
Only to discover months later
是克拉苏亲自寄出的那封信
Crassus himself had sent the message,
目的就是要市政官拿到手
intending for the Aedile to lay hands upon it,
按他的想法行动
and move in direction desired.
我也截到过克拉苏的信件
I too intercepted message from Crassus.
利用搜集到的信息
And used what was gleaned
为他铺平了统率大军的道路
to clear path for him to assume command.
你将恐惧深深地印在了共和国的心脏里
You have struck fear into the very heart of the Republic.
试想那个打败你的人
Imagine the glory that awaits…
该享有多大的荣光
the man who defeats you.
赫拉克里奥运来的比想象中的少
Heracleo delivers less than expected.
口粮必须再折半分配
Rations must be lowered by another half.
我们会坚持下去
We will make due.
直到克拉苏夺回这座城市
Until Crassus reclaims the city.
善出奇兵的人可不止他一个
He does not stand the only one capable of the unexpected.
我们去找赫拉克里奥
Let us seek Heracleo,
让全知全能的克拉苏大吃一惊吧
and a future even the mighty Crassus will not see coming.
再派一千人去援助昆提尔斯
Dispatch another thousand men to aid Quinctius.
我们必须加快速度了
We must see progress hastened.
遵命
Imperator.
代我行使权力
My word and my will.
你明白这意味着什么吗
You understand what that means?
明白 父亲
Yes, Father.
真的吗
Do you?
我的第一场战斗 以斯巴达克斯的胜利
The first battle in my campaign forever etched in history.
永远载入史册了
As a victory for Spartacus.
- 父亲 - 在我带主力部队到达之前
- Father… - He was not to be engaged
不要打草惊蛇
until I arrived with proper force.
难道我说得不够清楚吗
Was command not fucking clear?!
很清楚
It was.
但当斯巴达克斯出了城
Yet opportunity presented
可是千载难逢的机会呀
when Spartacus moved beyond city walls.
我认为不去把握才是大错
I thought it greater offense not to seize moment.
我做过这样的决定
A decision I made by myself.
我小的时候
When I was yet a little boy.
抱歉没有遵守您的命令 父亲
Apologies for disobeying your command, Father.
你还年轻 这事情还可以谅解
A thing that could be forgiven in light of youth.
但你的部下私自撤退一事
Yet your men falling to retreat
却不能随便放过去
does not so easily slip from concern.
我命令他们坚守阵地
I ordered them to stand ground.
但他们还是逃了
Yet they fled.
因为他们畏惧敌人甚于他们的将军
Because they feared the enemy more than their commanders.
我们必须纠正这一错误认识
A false assumption we must see corrected.
您想让我受到怎样的惩罚
What punishment would you have me inflict?
以儆效尤
One to stand warning.
要他们知道承受克拉苏家族的怒火
That death at the hands of Spartacus
还不如死在斯巴达克斯手下
pales against the wrath of the House of Crassus.
十一抽杀律
Decimation?
自从马略时代
Not since the days of Marius
这么野蛮的制度就没有实行过了
has savage ritual been so commanded.
他想杀一儆百
He would make example.
在敌人面前抱头逃窜有什么结果
Of what befalls a man who turns heel in face of enemy.
都是我的错
The fault is mine.
我要是听你的命令守住阵地
Had I obeyed your order to stand ground…
军队自乱阵脚 四下奔逃
Our men broke rank and fled.
你别无选择
You were left absent choice.
我父亲也不给我选择
As my father now leaves me.
五十个人
Fifty men.
五十颗石头
Fifty stones.
五颗抹上了死亡的颜色
Five stained with the promise of death.
抽得好就能活下去
Draw well and live.
抽得不好
Draw poorly…
在别人逃走时 你留在我身边
You stayed at my side while the others ran.
我能活着都是因为你
I am yet from this world because of you.
别再想这件事
Place it from mind.
祈祷我抽到好签吧
And pray I draw well.
你不值得跟这些懦夫们一道抽签
You do not deserve to be placed at risk among cowards.
我会跟我父亲谈谈
I will talk to my father
求他把你从十一抽杀律的名单中去掉
and beg your removal from decimation.
这么做在他的眼里只会降低你的身份
The act would only diminish you in his eyes.
我绝不允许这种事发生
A thing I would never allow.
你是他的军团中最可敬的人
You stand most honorable in his legions.
怎会他妈的落得这般下场
And this is fucking reward!
我要遵命行事
I shall do as commanded.
和所有的士兵一样
As all soldiers must.
这儿比马厩还臭
The stables were a sweeter smell.
卡斯特斯
Castus.
赫拉克里奥在哪儿
Where is Heracleo?
上次看到他时 他正喝酒玩女人呢
He was heavy with drink and whores last I laid eyes.
到他船上的甲板找找吧
Seek him upon deck of his ship.
谁都知道
The man has a well known preference
那家伙最喜欢在海上干事了
for sea and cunt, spread equally before him.
多谢
Gratitude.
来吧 喝一杯 我们一道去找他
Come, share cup, and we shall seek him together.
我们不跟你这种贱人一起走
We would not wallow in such low company.
我们还有要事在身
We are moved by pressing business.
有空再喝吧
Another time.
你想搞那小子
You wish to fuck the man,
介绍两句然后掏老二呗
make introduction and present cock.
我宁愿吃屎也不找那家伙
I would sooner caress shit and call it lover.
西利西亚人不能信
Cilicians cannot be trusted.
你很了解他们吗
You are familiar with their kind?
我以前和这种人相处过
I have had the displeasure of their company,
很不愉快
in years past.
说话要当心
Choose words with care.
斯巴达克斯当他们是盟友呢
Spartacus calls them fucking ally.
你不同意这说法
You do not share opinion?
我同不同意顶屁用
It would hold no fucking matter.
我只是鞍前马后
I am but humble servant
为伟大首领卖命的仆人
to the will of our glorious leader.
我听到传言
I have heard rumor.
大家把斯巴达克斯奉为神明
Spartacus stands a god among his people.
为了他的大业 我多少次豁出性命
I have imperiled life for his cause many times.
在维苏威和凯洛河
At Vesuvius and Calor
还有很多战斗 数不胜数
and battles far too numerous in the counting.
攻占这座城的时候也是
Even in the taking of this fucking city.
结果眼睁睁看着残存的敌人
Only to witness remainder of enemy
还在城里活得好好的
spared within its walls.
辛苦到手的钱财上缴了
And coin honestly gained
拿去跟该死的西利西亚人
stripped from hand to forge bargain
做什么交易
with the fucking Cilicians.
难怪你要从进城的奴隶那里
But small wonder you are forced to relieve
弄点小钱 原来是逼不得已
what you can from those newly entering gate.
这点钱还远远不够
A fraction of what is owed to me.
我的家当都在这儿了
That is all I carry.
为了我们今后的友谊 收下吧
Consider it yours, toward our continued friendship.
跟友谊这稀罕物比起来也太少了吧
Too small a sum, to purchase so rare an item.
说不定我们能一起挣大钱呢
Perhaps together we can see it grow.
我们都能赚足银子
And both our fortunes rise.
抱歉
Apologies.
你不准说出去
I will not have you speak of this.
遵命 女主人
Yes, Domina.
我不再是女主人了
I no longer stand as such.
你可以叫我莱塔
You may call me Laeta.
我常常想成为你们家的奴隶
I often dreamed of being of your house.
你是洛厄斯家的吧
You were one of Laurus', were you not?
我无数次祈祷能够摆脱他
Many nights I laid prayers to be free of him.
但愿城池沦陷不是因为你的祈祷
If only city did not need to fall in their answering.
珍惜现在拥有的吧
Embrace what you have.
世事无常 瞬息万变
All can change in sudden moment.
去你的 贱人
There, you fucking cunt!
布瑞克提斯
Brictius!
斯巴达克斯明确下过令
Spartacus gave clear orders.
不准对这些人动手
No hands are to be laid upon these people.
是这罗马混蛋对我动手
This Roman shit laid hands upon me,
我经过时抓我衣服
snapping at robe as I passed.
我只想知道我妹妹的消息
I but entreated for word of my sister…
去你妈的妹妹
Fuck your sister!
敢拔出来 不想活了
Unleash cock, and find it severed.
他们的脑袋都应该砍了挂起来
All their fucking heads should be set upon pike.
谢谢您
Gratitude.
要谢就谢斯巴达克斯
Owed to Spartacus.
我倒是同意把你脑袋挂起来
I tend to agree about the pikes.
等等
Wait!
我的妹妹
My sister…
菲比娅
Fabia…
头发是亚麻色的 跟你女人一样
flaxen of hair, such as your woman.
求求你 告诉我她是否活着
I beg of you, I must know if she lives.
很多罗马人死了
Many Roman dead.
你再碰我们 就跟你妹妹黄泉相会了
You join sister perhaps, touch again one of us.
求求你们
Please.
我没见过她
I have not seen her.
我们像妈妈喂奶一样
护着这帮罗马混蛋
斯巴达克斯为什么放过他们
Why Spartacus allow them live?
对此我无法理解
I hold no understanding towards it,
不过我们得尊重他的意思
yet we shall honor desire.
这家伙的头我也想挂起来
甘尼克斯 我有话要说
Gannicus, I must have words.
小丫头不能喝不能操
None give little girl,
有什么好说的
not drink and fuck.
她说得很对
She makes valid argument.
你必须听一听
You must listen.
我发现了一件你们担心的事情
I have laid eyes upon something that lends worry.
我们这样有好多次了
We have taken to each other's arms many times.
却从来没这么爽过
Yet never have soared so high.
我们远离了罗马
We are far from Rome.
也就没有了束缚
And tethers that prevent such flight.
谢谢
Gratitude.
让我陪在你身边
For allowing me to stay by your side.
我不会让你离开的
I would never have you leave it.
你的存在让我感到特别安心
Your presence gives much needed comfort.
很费心吧
It must weigh mind.
斯巴达克斯的事
This war with Spartacus.
他只是根肉刺 很快就会拔除
He is but nuisance, soon to fade from memory.
我忧心的是身边的人
My thoughts churn upon closer relation.
你说过提比略的伤势已经好了
You have said Tiberius' wounds already mend.
接下来他还是能代你行使权力
He will stand your word and will in coming days.
责任太重 我怀疑他根本背负不起
A weight I question placing again on so green a sapling.
在父亲如阳光般的指导下
He grows stronger each day
他每天都茁壮成长
beneath warming sun of father's guidance.
提比略倒是努力想要取悦我
Ah, Tiberius has given all to please me,
希望建功立业
to become honored soldier.
可每当我看到他
Yet when eyes are greeted,
我看到的只是一个孩子
there stands only a child before me.
在玩成人的游戏
Playing at the games of men.
他为罗马的荣耀浴血奋战过
He has fought and bled for the glory of Rome.
为他的统帅
For his Imperator.
难道他不配作为你的部下
Does he not deserve to be treated
受到同等的对待吗
as any other beneath your command?
我对你们的困境表示同情
You know I stand sympathetic toward your plight.
我们的人数超出了预料
Our numbers have unexpectedly swelled.
我们只能提供力所能及的帮助
My men and I can only provide what we ourselves can lay hand upon.
这还不够
It is not enough.
如果没有多余的嘴巴
Perhaps it would be,
吃那些粮食的话 应该是够的
if resources were not drained by undeserving mouths…
你跑题了
You stray from subject.
而你不理智
As you from reason.
你以为罗马人也会对你们一样心慈手软吗
Do you think they would treat your people with such kindness?
我们不是罗马人
We are not Romans.
也不会效仿他们惨无人道的行为
Nor shall we become them by acts of unnecessary cruelty.
不可理喻
This fucking man!
那我便尽我所能
I will provide you with what I can
喂饱你的慈悲心肠
to feed the lofty ideals.
但恐怕达不到你的要求
Yet fear, it shall fall short of desired mark.
我要改变计划
I would see target adjusted,
制定更确切的目标
and center struck with surer purpose.
你想修改合约条款
You wish to alter terms of our agreement?
我只想加点内容
I would but add to it,
让你的船装满更有赚头的货物
and see your ships filled with more promising cargo.
纳美特斯人
Nemetes!
有话跟你说
I would have words.
先让我他妈的干掉这杯
And I would finish fucking drink.
该死的高卢人
Fucking Gauls.
跟色雷斯人一样操蛋
Shitholes rivaling the Thracians…
我又不是你养的狗
I am not fucking cur!
高卢人
Gauls.
滚回去继续喝酒玩女人
Return to drink and whores,
不然就从这个世界消失
or part from this world.
你们自己选
Choose.
你不用搞这么粗暴吧 给谁看呢
You did not need to be so rough in demonstration.
我们都要尽自己的职责
We both must play our part.
快说你有什么发现
Now speak about what have you discovered?
那人不爱罗马
The man holds no love for Rome,
听他的言论就知道了
through weight of his words.
你怎么知道他说的是实话
How do you balance them against truth?
我相信他的忠诚和我没两样
I believe his loyalties mirror my own.
但我还要最后考验一次
Yet I will set final test,
看看他言行是否一致
and gauge action against words.
如果他说的是谎话 那人必有问题
If words prove false, so does the man.
查清楚
See it done.
自个儿兄弟都这么粗暴啊 是常有的事吗
A common thing, to be so rudely handled by a brother?
他不是我的兄弟
Ah, he stands no brother to me.
没有赢得我信任的人都不是我兄弟
Nor any man that has not earned my trust.
我就怕破坏了好兴致
I fear mood has taken sour turn.
来
Come.
我们喝酒高兴高兴
Let us sweeten it with drink.
我看还是拿更有意思的东西高兴吧
I would set desire towards greater spoils.
一边高兴 一边瞧瞧你的真面目
And in the revealing of them, set true nature to light…
这个美人
This precious jewel
曾是城里很多奴隶的女主人
once stood domina to many slaves within the city.
他们满足她的一切需求
They attended her every need.
她现在反过来满足我们了
As she now attends ours…
斯巴达克斯允许这样吗
Spartacus allows this?
去他妈的 当然不准
Fuck the gods, no.
他拿我的钱去享受了
He helped himself to my fucking coin.
而我的回报
I returned favor…
就是玩弄他的小宠物
with one of his little pets.
证明你不是这些人的朋友
Prove yourself no friend to these people.
拿这个罗马人爽一爽
Use this Roman for untold pleasures.
等你爽完了
And when you have finished,
记得在她身上划一刀
leave fresh mark upon her.
我们经常这么干
As we have so often done.
你先出去
Leave us.
别慌 不要害怕
Calm yourself, calm yourself.
我和你一样 也是罗马人
I stand a Roman, as you.
我叫盖乌斯•尤利乌斯•恺撒
My name is Gaius Julius Caesar.
我奉马科斯•克拉苏之命而来
I come in the name of Marcus Crassus.
他的军团正在北方集结
His legions are gathering in the north.
我们会攻下这座城
We shall take this city,
让所有蹂躏你的那些畜生万劫不复
and see all those who have done this to you suffer.
送我走吧
Free me…
克拉苏很快就来了
Soon Crassus will come.
我向你保证
You have my word.
送我走吧
Free me…
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
菲比娅
Fabia.
我们不会忘了你的名字
Know that it shall not be forgotten.
也不会饶恕折磨你的那些人
Nor the men that set you upon this fate.
你干了什么 你个疯子
What have you done, you mad fuck?!
我送她上路了
I set her free.
斯巴达克斯保护的罗马人都该如此
As I would all Romans yet held by Spartacus.
你真是我们当中的一员
You truly do stand one of us.
来吧 兄弟
Come, brother.
我们一起去做
Let us see it done.
没有什么比战火淬炼的兄弟情谊
There stands no stronger bond between men,
更为牢固
than one forged in war.
没有什么荣耀
Nor greater glory
比为保卫祖国罗马而牺牲更为光彩
than to fall in defense of mother Rome.
你们每个人都曾宣誓效忠
Each of you swore sacramentum.
服从命令
To obey order given.
不偷窃 不犯法
To refrain from theft or breach of common law.
遵守军规军纪
To protect the Legionary Standard.
永不溃散 永不脱逃
And never to break rank nor flee from enemy.
而站在我面前的这些人
Those who stand before me
在战场上临阵脱逃
turned from field of battle.
面对逆贼斯巴达克斯及其奴隶走狗
Retreated from the rebel Spartacus
只顾抱头逃命
and his army of slaves,
畏惧敌人更甚于畏惧自己的将军
fearing them more than their own commander.
这一错误
An error
今晚必须纠正过来
this night I shall see corrected.
经此教训
And in the lesson,
知道你们应该畏惧的名字
lay fear upon proper name.
马科斯
Marcus.
莱基尼亚
Licinius.
克拉苏
Crassus.
凡在十一抽杀律中幸存的人
Those who survive decimation
将被放逐到侍从营地
shall be banished to the followers camp.
与奴隶和妓女为伍
To live among slaves and whores
直到某天 我认为可以恢复你们的地位
until such a day I deem you worthy of proper company.
父亲 我有话想说
Father, I would have word…
我现在不是你的父亲
I am not your father in this.
我是你的统帅
I am your fucking imperator.
我不能再拿你当孩子看待了 提比略
I have too long considered you a child, Tiberius.
抱歉
Apologies.
你现在是个战士
You stand a soldier now,
应该与其他战士受到同样的对待
and deserve to be treated as any other.
跟他们站到一起
Join your men.
服从命令
Fall to command.
抽签
Draw lots.
我们永远不会忘记今夜
Let this night be forever remembered.
耻辱永远不要重现
And cause never repeated.
看看你们是何命运
Present your fates.
不 不 我操
No, no, fuck!
你不能这么做
You cannot do that!
真抱歉只有这么点儿
Apologies there is so little.
食物严重不足
Food grows scarce.
你为我们冒生命危险
You risk life for us.
我们不能有更多要求了
There is no more we can ask of you.
告诉你们一个好消息
See heart lifted with welcomed news.
克拉苏带领的军团
Crassus and his legions
距离我们只有一天的行军路程
are but a day's march from our city.
他会夺回这座城
He will retake it,
结束我们受苦受难的生活
and in the act end our suffering…
只怕你的苦难才刚开始
I fear it has just begun.
抱歉 莱塔
Apologies, Laeta.
我必须把我知道的告诉他们
I had to tell them what I saw.
错在我
The fault is my own.
竟然相信一个造反的奴隶
For laying trust in a rebellious slave!
住手
Hold!
这个男人
This man.
埃提斯就是帮他逃出来的吗
He is the one Attius helped free?
那个铁匠不知道这件事情
The blacksmith held no knowledge of it.
你朋友死了 就因为她
Your friend dead, because of her.
把他们绑起来 带到斯巴达克斯那里
See them bound and taken to Spartacus.
交给他来处理
They are his concern.
你去哪儿
Where do you go?
洗雪埃提斯的冤情
To see memory of Attius well fucking honored!
没有可疑的人吗
None give rise to suspicion?
他们都渴望罗马人的血
They are eager for Roman blood.
与真心加入我们的人一样
As any true to our cause should be.
菲比娅 菲比娅
Fabia…Fabia!
纳美特斯人
Nemetes!
快说 你抱的是谁
Break fucking words, and knowledge of what you carry!
一个失踪的罗马人
One of the missing Romans!
她从暗处冲出来攻击我
She came at me out of the shadows
半死不活还想逃跑
half dead from attempted escape.
多亏有莱西克斯
If it had not been for Lyciscus…
你不杀他们 他们就是这样感恩
You spare their lives, and this is fucking gratitude!
罗马人去死
Fuck the Romans!
宰掉罗马混蛋
Fuck the Roman cunts!
杀死罗马人
Kill the fucking Romans!
操他妈的
Fuck this.
所有罗马人都该被干掉
All should be struck from this world.
- 罗马人去死 - 就像你干掉埃提斯一样
- Fuck the Romans! - As you struck Attius from it?
那件事已经过去了 甘尼克斯
Subject has been laid to rest, Gannicus.
真相也一起埋没了
Along with fucking truth.
他帮助囚犯逃跑
He aided the prisoners in escape.
我发现后 他还想杀我
And made attempt on my life when I discovered…
是市政官的妻子放了他们
The Aedile's wife saw them free!
你是怎么知道的
How do you come upon this?
莱塔把他们藏在她丈夫的马厩底下
Laeta hid them beneath the floor of her husband's stables.
萨克莎把他们带到斯巴达克斯那里去了
Saxa carries her and the others to Spartacus.
有什么关系
It holds no matter.
埃提斯是罗马人 他就是活该
Attius was a Roman, who fell to deserved fate.
他是我朋友 你个疯婊子
He was my friend, you mad bitch!
闭嘴 兄弟
Seize tongue, brother…
揍他 甘尼克斯
Get him, Gannicus!
杀了他 打死这个混蛋
Kill him, get the fucker!
让我们看看你的本事 甘尼克斯
Let's see what you're made of, Gannicus!
上啊 揍他
Come on, hit him!
甘尼克斯
Gannicus!
冷静
Calm yourself…
去你的
Fuck you!
来啊
Come on!
起来
Get up!
甘尼克斯
Gannicus!
我别无选择
He left me no choice.
他保护罗马人
He protects the Romans!
我们那位伟大的首领也一样
As does our mighty fucking leader!
我们拼了命造反难道就是为了这个吗
Is this what we have risked all for in joining cause?!
斯巴达克斯有令
Spartacus gives command!
我愿意赔上性命
And I would give my life,
也要让敌人的热血溅到我脸上
to feel enemy's blood hot upon cheek.
我们的命是斯巴达克斯给的
We owe Spartacus our own lives.
但这事情他做错了
Yet he is wrong in this.
大家都知道
A thing known by all.
为了那些蹂躏过你的畜生
For every unwanted touch placed upon you.
为了曾经戴过的项圈
For every chain around neck,
背上承受的鞭笞
and every lash upon back!
拿罗马人的血来偿还
Take Roman blood as payment…
我们要真正占领这座城
and let us see this city truly ours!
我不能动手
I will not do this.
你必须服从命令
You shall do as commanded.
这是士兵的天职
As all soldiers must.
开始执行
Let it be done!
开始
Begin!
不
No!
我学到教训了
Your lesson well learned.
统帅
Imperator.
这想法是一天比一天疯狂
Each day brings new madness.
下次你就要让我从天上摘月亮下来了
Next you will ask to join in wresting moon from fucking heavens.
他的要求没那么不着边际
He sets purpose towards more earthly goal.
我所说的事情 有可能办到吗
Does it lie within possibility, what I seek to do?
什么梦都能成真
All dreams are possible…
只要你别从梦里醒过来就行了
it is but effort and cost that keeps it from waking grasp.
完成了我这最后一个要求
See this last thing that I ask of you to its end,
我保证你的船上
and I will fill your ship
装满城里的所有财物
with all the riches this city yet holds.
那就成交了 兄弟
Let us see it done then, brother!
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
克雷斯他们都疯了
Crixus and the others have gone mad.
他们在杀罗马人
They're killing the Romans.
看好西利西亚人
Keep watch over the Cilicians.
看来你很喜欢跟他们在一起
You seem to favor their fucking company.
- 快走 快 - 走 快走
- Move, quickly! - Come on, quick!
对不起
Uh, sorry.
你们不能停
Oh, you must keep moving.
我们走不到宅子的
We will not make it to the villa.
走不到了
No, you will not.
这是带给斯巴达克斯的
These for Spartacus.
别挡老娘的道
Take from fucking path!
甘尼克斯不在这里
I do not see Gannicus among you.
那就用不着怕他的婊子了
Nor cause to heed his bitch!
真不用怕吗
I give cause.
贱人
Bitch.
还有罗马人
More Romans!
我的天 放开他
Oh my God please, hands off him!
市政官的妻子
The Aedile's wife!
你给我恢复理智
You will regain sense!
不然就死在这里
Or fall where you stand!
失去理智的是你
It is you who has lost sense.
市政官的妻子
And the Aedile's wife
就是害你栽跟头的人
who has seen you tumble from perch.
就是她帮着那群罗马混蛋逃跑
She is the one who helped these Roman shits slip bond!
谎话连篇 倒在你面前装得挺像
And smiled at you through fucking lies!
这是事实
A thing of truth.
埃提斯没有参与其中
Attius held no part in it.
他也不该有那样的下场
Nor did he deserve the end that he met.
我待你仁慈 你就这样回报我
This is return for the mercy I grant you?
仁慈
Mercy?
你杀死了我丈夫
You robbed me of my husband.
你的手下在城里屠杀了成百上千的人
Your people slaughtered thousands within my city.
我现在就因为
And I now stand condemned,
救了几个人 便罪无可恕了吗
for trying to save but a handful from such cruelty?
这是从我们的罗马主人那里学到的
Learned at the hand of our Roman master.
杀了她 兄弟
Take her life, brother.
然后我们就能重归于好
And in the act let us become as one again.
理所应当
A thing deserved.
但我岂能跟我们的敌人一路货色
Yet I will not see us become the very thing we fight against.
很多人在这件事情上质疑你
There are many who question your mind in this.
我也有疑虑
I question mind as well…
为何信任你 让你肩担重任
placing faith in you as a leader.
把幸存的罗马人带到我的宅子里去
See the Romans that yet live gathered within my villa.
再有人胆敢违抗我的命令
Make further attempt against my will…
就跟今晚你们杀掉的人一个下场
follow those you have struck down this night.
他帮了我们很多很多
The man has helped us more than anyone.
但如今我怀疑他走错了路
Yet I now doubt path he travels.
也许是时候 走我们自己的路了
Then perhaps the time has come, to forge our own.